Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Archives Moving Images Collection, ca. 1928-2001 UA.Film.Video
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Promotional, III.
  - Video, 57 items
    - The University of Pittsburgh New Stadium, Practce Facility, & Convo Center, unknown; VHS T-15 (Box 9, Video 158)
    - Pitt: The Pride is Back, November 15, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 (Box 21, Video 583)
    - Werner Chepelsky & Partners - Mellon Bank - "Young Couple" YMCT-5788, unknown; VHS 30 Minute (Box 42, Video 907)
    - Werner Chepelsky & Partners - MELLON BANK - "MOM" YMCT-5905, unknown; VHS 30 Minute (Box 42, Video 910)
    - Werner Chepelsky & Partners - Mellon Bank - "Dad and Son" YMCT-5576, unknown; VHS 30 Minute (Box 42, Video 914)
    - University of Pittsburgh Werner Chepelsky & Partners "Get You", July 1, 1988; VHS 30 Minute (Box 43, Video 959)
    - "University of Pittsburgh" / Kerry, February 2, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 7, Video 122)
    - "Renaissance Pittsburgh", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA-20 14:30 (Box 7, Video 119)
    - "A New Attitude", unknown; VHS T-120 Needs Case (Box 9, Video 175)
    - University of Pitt - Kerry, unknown; 1 Inch Videotape (Box 28, Video 533)
    - Follow the Sun - 1975, 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 24, Video 429)
    - "Pitt Signs" 10/5, unknown; Betacam SP 20 Minute Needs Case (Box 29, Video 564)
    - Our HG Show (??), unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBR 5s Needs Case (Box 39, Video 782)
    - "Say no To Drugs" PSA, December 10, 1987; 3/4 Inch U-matic 5BRS Bryan Hinkle Zeke Gadson (Box 7, Video 124)
    - Pitt Going Gold, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 43, Video 945)
    - Pitt Student Life, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 43, Video 948)
    - Coca-cola USA - A/C Coke Classic - KOCL 6373 "Cool Down" (:30) / KOCL 6353 "Shave" (:30), August 21, 1996; VHS T-10 (Box 43, Video 964)
    - Pitt Logo, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 48, Video 1106)
    - "Something to Offer", unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 46, Video 1052)
    - "Golden Panthers Fund" / "Strategy 21", November 2, 1990; VHS T-30 (Box 40, Video 849)
    - Honors Program / Campus of the Future - (1984), unknown; 1 Inch Videotape (Box 50, Video 1123)
    - "Pitt Has Arrived", March 2, 1988; 1 Inch Videotape (Box 50, Video 1127)
    - "Pitt Has Arrived" / Gore Video, March 2, 1988; 1 Inch Videotape (Box 50, Video 1124)
    - "Get You", July 1, 1988; 1 Inch Videotape (Box 50, Video 1125)
    - "A Major Change" / "Only the Beginning", unknown; 1 Inch Videotape 479 Master Broadcast (Box 50, Video 1129)
    - Pitt Project - "Follow the Sun", unknown; 1 Inch Videotape 479 Master Broadcast (Box 51, Video 1142)
    - Pitt Project Film X-Fers, unknown; 1 Inch Videotape 479 Master Broadcast (Box 52, Video 1154)
    - "Upwards" (Reel 1) and "Pitt the Multiversity" (Reel 2), August 14, 1986 and unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA 60 Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 52, Video 1155)
    - Conversation with Omar K. Moore: w/lab shots, University Center for Instructional Resources., February 2, 1972; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 1, Video 1164)
    - Things to do in math – Liberty Elementary School…University Center for Instructional Resources., unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 1, Video 1165)
    - Classroom innovation: McEwan School, Communications Center, unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1166)
    - Open classroom workshop for Teachers, CMU-University of Pittsburgh University Center for Instructional Resources, May 23, 1975; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1168)
    - The Chiyou Development Center of Hill House Association Communications Center, unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1169)
    - Hilltop Catholic High School open classroom. University Center for Instructional Resources, unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1170)
    - Curriculum Possibilities in Business Education, unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 1 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 2, Video 1172)
    - Curriculum Possibilities in Business Education, unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 2 of 2 Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 2, Video 1173)
    - Shady Lane School. Communications Center., unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/6 (Box 53, Video 1175)
    - For you the very stars are new. University Relations 1998, VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1225)
    - Visions beyond the Bluff. University of Pittsburgh School of Pharmacy, unknown; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 10, Video 1230)
    - "Academic Message - Athletic Venue", October 22, 2003; VHS T-15 One Minute Needs Case (Box 48, Video 1252)
    - Alumni Association Photo Montage, May 1999; VHS 7:46 (Box 48, Video 1,255)
    - Discovery Weekend Highlights, December 5, 2000; VHS 9:34 (Box 48, Video 1,256)
      Announcement of Legacy Laureate program and Capital Campaign.
  - Film, 19 items
    - #2 The Gift, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1052)
    - #16 Pitt the Multi-University, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1005)
    - #50 Pitt Masters Program in Teaching, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1032)
    - #52 Campus Scenes, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1034)
    - #52 Campus Scenes, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1036)
    - #53 Campus Shots, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1035)
    - #63 Engineering is Creative, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1016)
    - #63 Engineering is Creative, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1017)
    - #64 Tower of Learning, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1014)
    - #67 Login: Pitt Computer Center, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1061)
    - #70 The Urban Campus, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1010)
    - #70 The Urban Campus, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1011)
    - #70 The Urban Campus, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1012)
    - #70 The Urban Campus, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1013)
    - #71 Prime Time, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1015)
    - #75 Play the Pitt Way, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1049)
    - #75 Play the Pitt Way - Sound Track, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 48, Reel 1056)
    - "The Pitt Parade", April 16-20, 1951; 16mm film Media Room 4/8/4 (Box 48, Reel 1073)
    - "The Pitt Parade", January 29-February 1, 1951; 16mm film Media Room 4/8/4 (Box 48, Reel 1074)
- Lectures, IV.
  - Film
    - #14 Edwin Peterson Uses Visual Aids to Teach English Composition, 1964; 2 film Two short 16mm films totalling 75 film feet stored in individual cans within one larger can.6/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 1,078)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 1), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 947)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 2), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 946)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 3), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 948)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 4), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 950)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 5), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 967)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 6), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 949)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 7), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 942)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 8), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 969)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 9), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 941)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 10), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 960)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 11), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 945)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 12), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 944)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 13), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 943)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 14), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 958)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 15), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 955)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 16), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 966)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 17), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 954)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 18), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 953)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 19), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 952)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 20), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 951)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 21), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 957)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 22), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 956)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 23), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 961)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 24), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 965)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 25), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 964)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 26), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 968)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 27), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 963)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 28), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 962)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 29), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 960)
    - #76 Lectures on Sophomore Literature (Reel 30), unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/4 (Box 48, Reel 959)
  - Video
    - Jane Fonda - No Date, unknown; 1/2 Inch Videotape Tape 1 of ? Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1212)
    - Jane Fonda Lecture Student Union Ballroom, October 18, 1977; 1/2 Inch Videotape Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 6, Video 1201)
    - Dr. Geral J. Massey, Inaugural Lecture "Translation: Meanings last stand", December 2, 1993; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 6, Video 1202)
    - Dr. Bruce G. Buchanan, Provost Inaugural Lecture, "What Do Computers Have to do with Intelligence?", February 10, 1994; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 6, Video 1199)
    - Dr. Savio L-Y Woo, Provost Inaugural Lecture, "Knee Ligaments: Twenty Years and I Hardly Know You.", May 19, 1994; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 54, Video 1207)
    - Dr. John W. Williams, Provost Inaugural Lecture, "How Dare the Bishop Destroy the Apostle's Tomb: A Deconstructionist History of the Shrine and Saint James", March 17, 1994; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 6, Video 1198)
    - Sally Katzen 1994 Lazerow Lecture, November 1, 1994; VHS T-120 Archive Collection Room 17/6/7 (Box 10, Video 1229)
    - Carl Bernstein, November 11, 1979
    - Timothy Leary, November 18, 1976
    - John Ehrlichman, September 28, 1976
- Assorted, V.
  This series contains 76 miscellaneous videos from the collection. This series notably includes footage of the 1989 Butler Farm Show as well as the 1994 Pitt Varsity Marching Band.
  - Film, 43 items
    This section contains 43 miscellaneous films, most of which pertain to the University of Pittsburgh. It notably includes two tapes of footage from the Pitt/RMU Project.
    - #17 Report From Urban University-Pitt and its Community, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1004)
    - #17 Report From Urban University-Pitt and its Community, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1057)
    - #62 Hommage A Nadia Boulanger, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1058)
    - #65 UCI Film 'Sheer Craziness', unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1046)
    - #68 The Mayor Comes to Dinner, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1044)
    - #69 Mexican-American Children, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1060)
    - #72 The Moat Monster, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1042)
    - #77 Western Penitentiary University Program, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1047)
    - Skydiving, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1041)
    - 4/21/70, April 21, 1970; 16mm film Media Room 6/6/2 (Box 10, Reel 170)
    - Head Sync Punch = The Beep, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 4/8/4 (Box 10, Reel 1065)
    - Pitt/RMU Project, unknown; 16mm film Reel 1 of 2 Media Room 4/8/5 (Box 10, Reel 1076)
    - Pitt/RMU Project, unknown; 16mm film Reel 2 of 2 Media Room 4/8/5 (Box 10, Reel 1077)
    - Studio Arts Film of Workprint, unknown; 16mm film Media Room 5/6/5 (Box 10, Reel 1083)
  - Video, 33 items
    - Gov. & Arena Video, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 4, Video 165)
    - March-April Animation Pieces, February 27, 1985; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 4:00 (Box 7, Video 614)
    - Butler Farm Show, July 7, 1989; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBU-18 (Box 8, Video 127)
    - University of Pittsburgh ":30 Spot", January 22, 1987; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA-5 (Box 8, Video 341)
    - Pitt PSA's 5 x :30 Without KBL Tag, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 8, Video 343)
    - Pitt Band 1994, unknown; Betacam SP Needs Case (Box 9, Video 148)
    - Pitt Campus Shots - For Alma Mater, unknown; Betacam SP 10 Minute Needs Case (Box 9, Video 147)
    - General Nutrition Centers, unknown; Betacam SP 1. Gene-0027 :30 2. Gene-0050/Gene-0029 :30 *Piggyback 2x:15 3. QGAO-3324 (Box 9, Video 157)
    - Club Lounge Animation w/ Music, February 28, 2001; VHS T-15 Needs Case (Box 9, Video 159)
    - Lucrezia Record, unknown; Betacam SP 20 Minute (Box 9, Video 286)
    - Stadium Long Shot - Pitt Pep Rally, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 20 Needs Case (Box 22, Video 401)
    - Music, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 29, Video 568)
    - Music, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 32, Video 647)
    - Music, unknown; Betacam SP 20 Minute Needs Case (Box 39, Video 826)
    - "Murder Location Scottdale PA", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBU-18 (Box 29, Video 569)
    - Pittsburgh Today (Proposition 48), September 6, 1989; VHS T-120 (Box 29, Video 570)
    - Pitt Man-On-The Street, unknown; VHS T-70 (Box 29, Video 579)
    - Video, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 30, Video 596)
    - Billy Joel, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic Needs Case (Box 32, Video 668)
    - (unreadable) Hawaii, unknown; VHS (Box 39, Video 777)
    - Fox Movie Tone, unknown; VHS (Box 39, Video 785)
    - IC4A's, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 39, Video 797)
    - M. Dane Knight - 120 Brandywine Drive, McMurray, Pa, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 39, Video 807)
    - The Man Goes to Beaumont, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 39, Video 829)
    - Pitt Travel - September 14, 1990, Betacam SP 20 Minute (Box 41, Video 884)
    - Monongahelia Fire, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBR-20 (Box 43, Video 949)
    - Halftime, February 6, 1996; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 47, Video 1087)
    - Halftime Show, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 43, Video 954)
    - Traci Interview Window Dub for Melissa, unknown; VHS T-15 (Box 43, Video 966)
    - P4 - Pitt / Oakland, February 10, 1984; 3/4 Inch U-matic Tape 2 of 2 Needs Case (Box 46, Video 1055)
    - P5 - "B" Roll - Information Science, October 31, 1985?; 3/4 Inch U-matic Needs Case (Box 46, Video 1056)
    - P18 - Pitt / Oakland, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic Needs Case (Box 46, Video 1059)
    - Parachute, unknown; Betacam SP Needs Case (Box 48, Video 1109)
    - KDKA Don Cannon Review - Thomas Starzl Interview, January 2000
    - WQED Fred Friendly Show (Managing Our Miracles: Health Care in America) - Thomas Starzl Interview, 1986